Hey guys, welcome back.
Now, I graduated back in 2008 as a
computer science engineer and back in 2007 itself,
you know, I had an offer from TCS,
you know, it had come to my campus
as a first company for hiring the freshers
and I was lucky I was able to
crack the interview and so I had not
really faced any struggle getting my first job,
okay.
You know, life went on, I joined TCS,
I had my ups and downs, okay, but
after two years, I thought let me just
go out and try attending interviews outside and
I started giving interviews, one interviews, two interviews,
third interview, fourth interview, six, seven, probably around
eight, I think.
So, within span of a year after hitting
two years of experience till I hit my
three years of experience, I attended about seven
to eight interviews and I was not able
to crack an interview, that is when I
saw the real struggle, okay.
I was dejected, literally, I didn't know what
to do, you know, a good friend of
mine said, why don't you kind of get
trained from somebody else?
So, and then, you know, we got in
touch with our college senior, he said, hey,
go to this guy called Prabhakar, he teaches,
you know, Informatica ETL development and I, you
know, my friend and I went over there,
you know, talked to him and I enrolled
in his classes and, you know, within a
period of three months, I was able to
crack interviews, okay.
So, you know, why am I sharing this
with you?
You know, I had that hunger, you know,
the hunger was there to crack interviews and
because I was getting rejected time and again,
time and again, multiple times I got rejected,
okay, and that hunger made me really work
hard, okay, very hard and I'm really grateful
for my mentor, you know, from whom I
learned Informatica ETL development data engineering and back
then, I did not know that Informatica field
would change my life, you know, learning Informatica
would really have such a profound, in fact,
profound impact in my life, I didn't know
that because I didn't know back then that
data is an evergreen field, okay.
See, even now in the days of AI,
data engineers are always required, okay, it is
a field that needs interacting with business stakeholders,
interacting with a lot different teams.
So, it is a discipline in which there
is a lot to learn, a lot to
learn and I'll tell you back then I
learned Informatica, I did not really have any
real-world project to actually work on, you
know, I was taught Informatica very, very well
and, you know, I learned really well and
I remember after I learned, I finished training,
I took, I think, a week off from
my office just to do the hands-on,
I did the hands-on, I took the
screenshots of the different mappings I built in
Informatica, put them in a word doc, okay,
and I think I probably took color printouts
and I made my own notes, okay, I
still have that 27-page notes I made
myself, okay, I had typed in my laptop
27-page notes, why am I telling this
to you, okay, again back then I did
not really have a real world but that
hands-on really helped me and my notes
really helped me but what you are about
to embark upon now in this course is
truly game-changing, I believe, because you will
actually get to work on a real project
with real data, you will see how to
pull from the source, how to load data
into the data lake, how to transform it,
how to unit test it, how to orchestrate
the jobs, in the sense how to run
the job sequentially as such, okay, one by
one and how to schedule the job and
in doing so you'll also learn about how
to leverage AI for all data engineering tasks,
okay, now this whole course is highly fast
-paced, it's highly hands-on, this labs course
actually simulates working in a real world project
environment with real data, you will feel you're
working in the real world, we will use
real data that gets published every month, okay,
every month in fact, real data, I strongly
hope by the end of this course you
will feel that you finally found a course
that shows how data engineering is done end
-to-end in the real world, I don't
know of any Udemy course, any YouTube course
or any other instructor who is doing this,
if you do know, let me know, okay,
I would love to collaborate with him or
her because in that case the vibe would
match, now I'll tell you how to learn,
how to approach this particular course, okay, you
got to be replicating what I'm doing, whatever
I do, you should be doing at the
same time in your account and that's the
only way you'll grasp the depth that is
there in this project and this course is
truly hands-on and there is one more
course which has to be also consumed parallelly
which is a deep dive course, so these
two course should go parallelly, okay, you may
do some hands-on, you may also watch
the video from deep dive or you may
watch video from deep dive then come here
and do hands-on, so back and forth
you'll have to go through, even if you
have to go through this content once or
twice or even thrice, so be it, my
teaching style is straightforward, I don't like to
beat around the bush, so some videos are
really very short and crisp and even if
you have to really pause the video, then
do hands-on, then resume, so be it,
do that, okay, and if you truly get
this entire project story and if you can
replicate that in the interview, nothing like it,
so if you're really excited about this project,
this hands-on real world project with real
data, let me know in the comment below
by typing, I am excited and I will
do whatever it takes to complete the course,
I will do my hands-on, I really
want to see your commitment, so go ahead
and type it down below, I really look
forward to reading that and what should be
your goal always, your goal should always be
to crack multiple interviews and induct into the
DEH Hall of Fame by getting this award,
crack interviews, apply for the HUF award, get
interviewed by me and get this award delivered
to you, and don't just stop at this
award itself, you got to be thinking long
term, you got to be always looking at
how you can actually grow beyond your current
role to reach the architect level roles in
data engineering, okay, I'll talk to you in
the next video and before that, as I
said, type in the comment below, I am
really excited and I will do whatever it
takes to complete the hands-on in this
course, okay, I'll see you in the next
video.